<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>index on JoannaFlorenceMakes</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in index on JoannaFlorenceMakes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 11:42:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: Billie by Tilly and the Buttons</title><link>/blog/spr-billie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/spr-billie/</guid><description>&lt;p>This pattern is Billie by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a> and can be used to make a jumper as well as a jumper dress, with either regular or balloon sleeves. I chose to make the dress and chose the regular sleeve option!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love this dress, it is so perfect and comfortable, just like I wanted! It a great ultimate work from home dress and looks much more professional than PJs! I love it paired with leggings for ultimate comfort. For a less casual look I pair this dress with tights and combat books as pictured. Did I mention it has pockets!? They&amp;rsquo;re a great size and fit my big phone in them! They don&amp;rsquo;t make the dress look super bulky like some other patterns do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2022 Sewing Resolutions</title><link>/blog/resolutions-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/resolutions-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>Happy New Year! &amp;#x1f31f;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beginning of a new year is a great time to reflect on how we&amp;rsquo;d like the next 365 days (or so) to go for ourselves; what we&amp;rsquo;d like to achieve and ways to reach these goals! I&amp;rsquo;ve decided this year to set myself a few sewing resolutions (reSEWlutions if you will!) so I can spend more time creating things that I love and getting the most out of my hobby!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Christmas 2021 Dress</title><link>/portfolio/christmas-dress-2021/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Dec 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/christmas-dress-2021/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is the second time I&amp;rsquo;ve made the Joni dress by Tilly and the Buttons. It&amp;rsquo;s such a great pattern and the outcome is so gorgeous and comfortable at the same time due to the stretch. Last time I made it using the flared sleeve option, but this time I made fitted sleeves and extended them all the way down to my wrists. I&amp;rsquo;m so happy with the outcome&amp;hellip; what a great Christmas party dress!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dachshund Dungarees</title><link>/portfolio/dachshund-dungarees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/dachshund-dungarees/</guid><description>&lt;p>I made these custom dungarees for my sister Jay, who is modelling them here. Don&amp;rsquo;t you think she looks fab? The fabric is tapestry fabric covered in dachshunds! The pattern is K4138 by Kwik Sew. I have used the pattern before to sew the pinfore dress variation for myself. This took a lot of effort but I think it was worth it!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Skull Hoodie</title><link>/portfolio/skull-hoodie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/skull-hoodie/</guid><description>&lt;p>This hoodie is so cosy, I never want to take it off!&lt;br>
The pattern is Stella, from the book Stretch by Tilly and the Buttons.&lt;br>
The fabric is French terry and was gifted to me by &lt;a href="https://minerva.com">Minerva&lt;/a>. I also lined the hood in plain black fleece for extra cosiness! I added a pattern-matched kangaroo pocket on the front.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: Lyra by Tilly and the Buttons</title><link>/blog/lyra-dress/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/lyra-dress/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yet another gorgeous dress by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a>. This one features a relaxed waist with a button up front and shirt collar. The different options for sleeve length and dress length mean that this dress can be turned into an easy-to-wear summer dress just as easily as it can be turned into a toasty winter dress.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- &lt;span class="rate-heading">Rating:&lt;/span>


&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>

&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>

&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>
 -->
&lt;p>The options I went for were:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The knee length variation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The short sleeve variation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The optional waist tie.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I accidentally cut the sleeves out at a length that was more 3/4 length than short sleeved. Although I could have chopped off a few inches to get down to the short sleeve length, I decided I quite liked the 3/4 length variation I&amp;rsquo;d created!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Lyra Dress</title><link>/portfolio/lyra-dress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/lyra-dress/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yet another gorgeous dress by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a>!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The variations I went for were:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Knee length dress.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3/4 length sleeves.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The optional waist tie.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The fabric I used was kindly gifted to me by &lt;a href="https://minerva.com">Minerva&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I took my time to make this dress and I think because of that it turned out to be the best item that I have made to date!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: Winslow Culottes by Helen's Closet</title><link>/blog/winslow-culottes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/winslow-culottes/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Winslow Culottes are a beginner-friendly pattern by &lt;a href="https://helensclosetpatterns.com/">Helen&amp;rsquo;s Closet&lt;/a>, featuring box pleats and an invisible zipper at the back. This is the first pattern that I’ve bought from Helen’s Closet and I have to say that I am super impressed. The pattern comes with four different length options. The one I chose to sew is view A (the shortest) but I’m definitely going to make some more in longer lengths.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Joni Dress</title><link>/portfolio/joni-dress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/joni-dress/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Joni pattern is by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a> and features in the book &lt;em>Stretch!&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am IN LOVE with this dress. It features a flattering empire waistline with a beautiful twist on the front as well as a full circle skirt. I opted for the flared sleeve variation.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Self Drafted Shirred Top</title><link>/portfolio/shirred-top/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/shirred-top/</guid><description>&lt;p>This pattern was entirely self drafted - yay!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The bodice was so simple to make and started as just two rectangles! The shirring took a long time but it creates a great fit and is so easy to wear.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My overlocker was in for repair when I made this so it was a great chance to practice my French seams!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: Joni by Tilly and the Buttons</title><link>/blog/joni-dress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/joni-dress/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Joni pattern is by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a> and features in the book &lt;em>Stretch!&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- &lt;span class="rate-heading">Rating:&lt;/span>


&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>

&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>

&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>
 -->
&lt;p>I am IN LOVE with this dress. It features a flattering empire waistline with a beautiful twist on the front as well as a full circle skirt. The pattern also comes with a choice of sleeves to choose from: three-quarter length, elbow-length, flared or even ruched.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I opted for the flared sleeves, although I didn&amp;rsquo;t make them as flared as suggested in the book. The book tells you how to create the pattern for the flared sleeves and in step 2 tells you to spread the pieces 10cm (4in) apart. I opted for 8cm instead and I love the amount of flare my sleeves have.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Brighter Days Ahead Rainbow</title><link>/portfolio/brighter-days/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/brighter-days/</guid><description>&lt;p>This beautiful design is by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/wimperisembroidery/">Niamh Wimperis&lt;/a>. I saw it on the cover of Mollie Makes magazine and knew I had to stitch it. I gifted it to my auntie for her birthday &lt;i class="bi bi-emoji-smile">&lt;/i>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tilly and the Buttons: Safiya Trousers</title><link>/blog/safiya-trousers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/safiya-trousers/</guid><description>&lt;p>This pattern is included in the &lt;em>Make it Simple&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a> book that I got for my birthday recently! I&amp;rsquo;ve never made a pair of trousers before (unless you count PJs) and due to the temperature getting warmer and the sun coming out I thought I should make some nice lightweight summer trousers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fabric used is a linen-cotton mix from &lt;a href="https://poundfabrics.co.uk/">Pound Fabrics&lt;/a> and it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely perfect for lightweight summer clothes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Safiya Trousers</title><link>/portfolio/safiya-trousers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/safiya-trousers/</guid><description>&lt;p>These are the Safiya Trousers from the Tilly and the Button&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;Make it Simple&amp;rdquo;. They are super comfy. As the book says, it&amp;rsquo;s almost like I&amp;rsquo;m secretly wearing pyjamas!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With this pattern I also succeeded at pattern matching for the first time - yay!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tilly and the Buttons: Tabitha T-Shirt</title><link>/blog/tabitha-t-shirt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/tabitha-t-shirt/</guid><description>&lt;p>I've been wanting to try out a &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a> pattern for a while now. I&amp;rsquo;m constantly looking at their Instagram page, and loving how aesthetically pleasing it is! I love how they cater to all skill levels and I refer to their blog and Youtube channel frequently because of how clearly everything is explained.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got the &amp;ldquo;Make it Simple&amp;rdquo; Tilly and the Buttons book for my birthday recently and immediately went through the book sticking post-it flags on the pages of the patterns I wanted to try first. Learning to properly sew with stretch fabrics has been a goal of mine for a while, so when I saw that the book had an easy T-shirt pattern I knew that I had to try it. T-shirts are an absolute wardrobe staple and because I&amp;rsquo;m working from home at the moment due to Covid, they are what I wear almost every day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: The Great British Sewing Bee Shell Top</title><link>/blog/shell-top/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 11:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/shell-top/</guid><description>&lt;p>Shell tops aren't really my style but after watching the first episode of The Great British Sewing Bee, series 7, I felt inspired to make one myself. I was mainly intrigued by the &amp;ldquo;bagging out&amp;rdquo; technique for the facing which I had never tried and wanted to learn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pattern I used is free to download as a PDF and is a very similar shell top to the one used in the episode. It can be found on Sew Mag&amp;rsquo;s website &lt;a href="https://www.sewmag.co.uk/free-sewing-patterns/sewing-bee-sleevless-shell-top">here&lt;/a>. In fact, I think this pattern is from a previous seris of The Sewing Bee!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: The Amelia Tea Dress</title><link>/blog/amelia-tea-dress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/amelia-tea-dress/</guid><description>&lt;p>Not only is this 50's inspired vintage tea dress absolutely beautiful but the shirred waist and fluttery sleeves make it super comfortable and perfect for the summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fabric used was from the sale at &lt;a href="https://poundfabrics.co.uk/">Pound Fabrics&lt;/a> and is a lightweight polyester. It was easy and enjoyable to sew with (after I realised that some of my pins were ruining it so I stopped using them!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pattern was easy to follow although I found that there were a few small steps not included such as adding understitching to the neckline facing as well as how to neatly finish seams. I overlocked edges as I went and gave a rolled hem to the skirt for a nice finish.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Amelia Tea Dress</title><link>/portfolio/amelia-dress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/amelia-dress/</guid><description>&lt;p>I absolutely LOVE this pattern. It&amp;rsquo;s The Amelia Tea Dress by Simple Sew&amp;hellip; with a few hacks. Firstly, I added some big pockets and attached them in-seam at both the side seams and waist. Secondly, as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough fabric for the original pattern I shortened the skirt pattern piece so I was still able to cut out a full circle skirt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Techniques I learnt in the process were:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Be Kind to Your Mind</title><link>/portfolio/be-kind-to-your-mind/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/be-kind-to-your-mind/</guid><description>&lt;p>I first added watercolour to the unbleached calico fabric. Then I traced on my design and started stitching! &lt;br>I love this phrase and it&amp;rsquo;s definitely something I need to tell myself more often as I am always criticising my work and comparing myself to others. I&amp;rsquo;m sure that others can relate!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free Embroidery Pattern: Flowery Skull</title><link>/blog/skull-pattern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/skull-pattern/</guid><description>&lt;p>I absolutely love gothic-esque embroidery and I was inspired by the beautiful Mexican Day of the Dead sugar skulls to create this flowery skull pattern. I have stitched it in a 5&amp;quot; hoop on calico fabric but I also think it would look great on a tote bag, on a denim jacket, or as a patch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can download the pattern below. To fit the pattern in a 5&amp;quot; hoop make sure your printer does not scale the page, but feel free to scale if you would like the pattern to be smaller or larger.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Strawberry Pinafore Dress</title><link>/portfolio/strawberry-dress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/strawberry-dress/</guid><description>&lt;p>When I saw this strawberry covered fabric I immediately thought about making a summery pinafore dress. Then when I saw this pattern for a pinafore dress with large pockets &lt;em>and&lt;/em> a pocket on the front I knew I had to make it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pattern used was Kwik Sew K4318.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Techniques I learnt in the process were:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Sewing a lapped zip.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Turning corners neatly on an overlocker.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stitch in the ditch.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A refresher on gathering.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>A refresher on using my machine to sew one-step buttonholes.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I also had a stark reminder not to grade seams too much or else things start falling apart!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I love my dachshund!</title><link>/portfolio/sausage-dog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/sausage-dog/</guid><description>&lt;p>My friend was getting rid of a load of old bed sheets and in them was this gorgeous duvet cover printed with dachshunds, spots, bones and paw prints.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love recycling fabric and it was great to use this black and tan dachshund as a focal point for a decorative hoop.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve still got loads of the fabric left so it&amp;rsquo;ll definitely feature again in the future!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Stitches used: Chain stitch, stem stitch, back stitch.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Monochrome Blue</title><link>/portfolio/monochrome-girl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/monochrome-girl/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 2021 I&amp;rsquo;ve been particpating in the monthly &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/stitchthisinyourstyle/">@stitchthisinyourstyle&lt;/a> challenge. I love this challenge because it really gets my creative juices flowing every month with a &amp;ldquo;prompt&amp;rdquo; to work into a design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>March&amp;rsquo;s prompt was &amp;ldquo;monochrome&amp;rdquo; so I stitched this &amp;ldquo;blue&amp;rdquo; girl using several different shades of blue.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Floral Asymmetrical Dress</title><link>/portfolio/floral-dress/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/floral-dress/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is actually the first dress I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully completed without giving up halfway through! I&amp;rsquo;ve had some sort of mental block about dresses until now. I’ve made plenty of tops and skirts but a dress just seemed like an entirely more difficult thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pattern used was New Look 6507 (view C&amp;hellip; with the adition of a strap).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Techniques I learnt in the process were:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>French seams.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Making bias binding.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Tricks for sewing over big chunky seams.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Narrow rolled hems.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>Something I found frustrating was using the rolled hem presser foot. It&amp;rsquo;s definitely something I need a lot more practice with!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Galápagos penguin</title><link>/portfolio/galapagos-penguin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/galapagos-penguin/</guid><description>&lt;p>One of the reasons I got into embroidery in the first place was because I saw thread-painted animals on Instagram and thought that they looked absolutely beautiful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a long while I put off this project because I was scared of doing an injustice to my favourite animal, the penguin. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier with how this turned out though!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a Galápagos penguin that I stitched as part of the February 2021 Endangered Species Challenge by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/rabbithatdesigns/">@rabbithatdesigns&lt;/a>. The background is watercolour on calico and the design was created by myself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Sleepy Sloth</title><link>/portfolio/sloth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/sloth/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently subscribed to Love Embroidery magazine and this beautiful pattern came in issue 10 (January 2021). It&amp;rsquo;s by Celeste Johnston of &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/lemon_made_shop/">@lemon_made_shop&lt;/a> and is printed in her book Freshly Stitched.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>About Me</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>&lt;head>
&lt;script async src="https://pagead2.googlesyndication.com/pagead/js/adsbygoogle.js?client=ca-pub-2155859976545968"
 crossorigin="anonymous">&lt;/script>
&lt;/head>
&lt;p class="intro-handwritten">Hi there!&lt;/p>
&lt;p class="separator">I'm Joanna, keen sewist and crafter! Most days you can find me making something with the help of my assistant, my miniature dachshund Charlie.
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve always loved crafts and grew up knitting and cross stitching. In 2020 I discovered the joy of sewing and I&amp;rsquo;ve been hooked ever since. I am largely self-taught, having learnt a lot through the wonderful online sewing community.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For the latest updates, follow my Instagram account &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/joannaflorencemakes">@joannaflorencemakes&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Welcome message</title><link>/welcomemessage/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/welcomemessage/</guid><description>&lt;!-- &lt;span class="four-words">DESIGN . EMBROIDERY . SEWING . CRAFTS&lt;/span> -->
&lt;p>&lt;span class="intro-handwritten">This is where I should write a fantastic intro&lt;/span>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Spill the tea!</title><link>/portfolio/spill-the-tea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/spill-the-tea/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 2021 I&amp;rsquo;ve been particpating in the monthly &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/stitchthisinyourstyle/">@stitchthisinyourstyle&lt;/a> challenge. I love this challenge because it really gets my creative juices flowing every month with a &amp;ldquo;prompt&amp;rdquo; to work into a design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Febuary&amp;rsquo;s prompt was &amp;ldquo;drink&amp;rdquo;. Because I’m British I obviously had to do something involving #tea.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My 2020 Mantra</title><link>/portfolio/things-wont/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/things-wont/</guid><description>&lt;p>2020 was a hard year for everyone and this phrase is what I&amp;rsquo;ve been telling myself throughout the entire pandemic.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Something I loved about doing this piece was the lettering. It took hours but it was so theraputic and totally worth it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Green Day Album Art</title><link>/portfolio/american-idiot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/american-idiot/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been enamoured with this album artwork and I saw it as a good design to practice my satin stitch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I restarted this piece three times. Originally I drew the design onto some black fabric but found it difficult to see the design accurately and so switched to calico and coloured the black background with a Sharpie. I kind of love the rusticity of it and I definitely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have got that with a plain black fabric.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Nope</title><link>/portfolio/nope/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/nope/</guid><description>&lt;p>In 2021 I&amp;rsquo;ve been particpating in the monthly &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/stitchthisinyourstyle/">@stitchthisinyourstyle&lt;/a> challenge. I love this challenge because it really gets my creative juices flowing every month with a &amp;ldquo;prompt&amp;rdquo; to work into a design.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>January&amp;rsquo;s prompt was &amp;ldquo;one word&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;Nope&amp;rdquo; pretty much sums up my January.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Dave the Dachshund</title><link>/portfolio/dave-the-dachshund/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/dave-the-dachshund/</guid><description>&lt;p>I originally found this free pattern for &amp;ldquo;Dave the Dachshund&amp;rdquo; online from &lt;a href="https://www.sewmag.co.uk/free-sewing-patterns/dave-dachshund-templates">Sew Magazine&lt;/a> after wanting to make a doorstop as a present for my sister&amp;rsquo;s birthday (it&amp;rsquo;s not just me that&amp;rsquo;s obsessed with dachshunds!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After that make, I decided I wanted to make Dave again, but with this super cute avocado fabric! I&amp;rsquo;d never made a soft toy before and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more pleased with how he turned out.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>