<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on JoannaFlorenceMakes</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on JoannaFlorenceMakes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 11:00:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: The Great British Sewing Bee Shell Top</title><link>/blog/shell-top/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 11:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/shell-top/</guid><description>Shell tops aren't really my style but after watching the first episode of The Great British Sewing Bee, series 7, I felt inspired to make one myself. I was mainly intrigued by the &amp;ldquo;bagging out&amp;rdquo; technique for the facing which I had never tried and wanted to learn.
The pattern I used is free to download as a PDF and is a very similar shell top to the one used in the episode.</description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: The Amelia Tea Dress</title><link>/blog/amelia-tea-dress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/amelia-tea-dress/</guid><description>Not only is this 50's inspired vintage tea dress absolutely beautiful but the shirred waist and fluttery sleeves make it super comfortable and perfect for the summer.
The fabric used was from the sale at Pound Fabrics and is a lightweight polyester. It was easy and enjoyable to sew with (after I realised that some of my pins were ruining it so I stopped using them!).
The pattern was easy to follow although I found that there were a few small steps not included such as adding understitching to the neckline facing as well as how to neatly finish seams.</description></item><item><title>Free Embroidery Pattern: Flowery Skull</title><link>/blog/skull-pattern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/skull-pattern/</guid><description>I absolutely love gothic-esque embroidery and I was inspired by the beautiful Mexican Day of the Dead sugar skulls to create this flowery skull pattern. I have stitched it in a 5&amp;quot; hoop on calico fabric but I also think it would look great on a tote bag, on a denim jacket, or as a patch.
You can download the pattern below. To fit the pattern in a 5&amp;quot; hoop make sure your printer does not scale the page, but feel free to scale if you would like the pattern to be smaller or larger.</description></item></channel></rss>