<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on JoannaFlorenceMakes</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on JoannaFlorenceMakes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 11:42:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: Joni by Tilly and the Buttons</title><link>/blog/joni-dress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/joni-dress/</guid><description>The Joni pattern is by Tilly and the Buttons and features in the book Stretch!.
I am IN LOVE with this dress. It features a flattering empire waistline with a beautiful twist on the front as well as a full circle skirt. The pattern also comes with a choice of sleeves to choose from: three-quarter length, elbow-length, flared or even ruched.
I opted for the flared sleeves, although I didn&amp;rsquo;t make them as flared as suggested in the book.</description></item><item><title>Tilly and the Buttons: Safiya Trousers</title><link>/blog/safiya-trousers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/safiya-trousers/</guid><description>This pattern is included in the Make it Simple Tilly and the Buttons book that I got for my birthday recently! I&amp;rsquo;ve never made a pair of trousers before (unless you count PJs) and due to the temperature getting warmer and the sun coming out I thought I should make some nice lightweight summer trousers.
The fabric used is a linen-cotton mix from Pound Fabrics and it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely perfect for lightweight summer clothes.</description></item><item><title>Tilly and the Buttons: Tabitha T-Shirt</title><link>/blog/tabitha-t-shirt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/tabitha-t-shirt/</guid><description>I've been wanting to try out a Tilly and the Buttons pattern for a while now. I&amp;rsquo;m constantly looking at their Instagram page, and loving how aesthetically pleasing it is! I love how they cater to all skill levels and I refer to their blog and Youtube channel frequently because of how clearly everything is explained.
I got the &amp;ldquo;Make it Simple&amp;rdquo; Tilly and the Buttons book for my birthday recently and immediately went through the book sticking post-it flags on the pages of the patterns I wanted to try first.</description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: The Great British Sewing Bee Shell Top</title><link>/blog/shell-top/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 11:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/shell-top/</guid><description>Shell tops aren't really my style but after watching the first episode of The Great British Sewing Bee, series 7, I felt inspired to make one myself. I was mainly intrigued by the &amp;ldquo;bagging out&amp;rdquo; technique for the facing which I had never tried and wanted to learn.
The pattern I used is free to download as a PDF and is a very similar shell top to the one used in the episode.</description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: The Amelia Tea Dress</title><link>/blog/amelia-tea-dress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/amelia-tea-dress/</guid><description>Not only is this 50's inspired vintage tea dress absolutely beautiful but the shirred waist and fluttery sleeves make it super comfortable and perfect for the summer.
The fabric used was from the sale at Pound Fabrics and is a lightweight polyester. It was easy and enjoyable to sew with (after I realised that some of my pins were ruining it so I stopped using them!).
The pattern was easy to follow although I found that there were a few small steps not included such as adding understitching to the neckline facing as well as how to neatly finish seams.</description></item><item><title>Free Embroidery Pattern: Flowery Skull</title><link>/blog/skull-pattern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/skull-pattern/</guid><description>I absolutely love gothic-esque embroidery and I was inspired by the beautiful Mexican Day of the Dead sugar skulls to create this flowery skull pattern. I have stitched it in a 5&amp;quot; hoop on calico fabric but I also think it would look great on a tote bag, on a denim jacket, or as a patch.
You can download the pattern below. To fit the pattern in a 5&amp;quot; hoop make sure your printer does not scale the page, but feel free to scale if you would like the pattern to be smaller or larger.</description></item></channel></rss>