<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blogs on JoannaFlorenceMakes</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blogs on JoannaFlorenceMakes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 11:42:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: Billie by Tilly and the Buttons</title><link>/blog/spr-billie/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jan 2022 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/spr-billie/</guid><description>&lt;p>This pattern is Billie by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a> and can be used to make a jumper as well as a jumper dress, with either regular or balloon sleeves. I chose to make the dress and chose the regular sleeve option!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I love this dress, it is so perfect and comfortable, just like I wanted! It a great ultimate work from home dress and looks much more professional than PJs! I love it paired with leggings for ultimate comfort. For a less casual look I pair this dress with tights and combat books as pictured. Did I mention it has pockets!? They&amp;rsquo;re a great size and fit my big phone in them! They don&amp;rsquo;t make the dress look super bulky like some other patterns do.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>2022 Sewing Resolutions</title><link>/blog/resolutions-2022/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/resolutions-2022/</guid><description>&lt;p>Happy New Year! &amp;#x1f31f;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The beginning of a new year is a great time to reflect on how we&amp;rsquo;d like the next 365 days (or so) to go for ourselves; what we&amp;rsquo;d like to achieve and ways to reach these goals! I&amp;rsquo;ve decided this year to set myself a few sewing resolutions (reSEWlutions if you will!) so I can spend more time creating things that I love and getting the most out of my hobby!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: Lyra by Tilly and the Buttons</title><link>/blog/lyra-dress/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/lyra-dress/</guid><description>&lt;p>Yet another gorgeous dress by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a>. This one features a relaxed waist with a button up front and shirt collar. The different options for sleeve length and dress length mean that this dress can be turned into an easy-to-wear summer dress just as easily as it can be turned into a toasty winter dress.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- &lt;span class="rate-heading">Rating:&lt;/span>


&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>

&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>

&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>
 -->
&lt;p>The options I went for were:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>The knee length variation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The short sleeve variation.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>The optional waist tie.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>I accidentally cut the sleeves out at a length that was more 3/4 length than short sleeved. Although I could have chopped off a few inches to get down to the short sleeve length, I decided I quite liked the 3/4 length variation I&amp;rsquo;d created!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: Winslow Culottes by Helen's Closet</title><link>/blog/winslow-culottes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/winslow-culottes/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Winslow Culottes are a beginner-friendly pattern by &lt;a href="https://helensclosetpatterns.com/">Helen&amp;rsquo;s Closet&lt;/a>, featuring box pleats and an invisible zipper at the back. This is the first pattern that I’ve bought from Helen’s Closet and I have to say that I am super impressed. The pattern comes with four different length options. The one I chose to sew is view A (the shortest) but I’m definitely going to make some more in longer lengths.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: Joni by Tilly and the Buttons</title><link>/blog/joni-dress/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/joni-dress/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Joni pattern is by &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a> and features in the book &lt;em>Stretch!&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;!-- &lt;span class="rate-heading">Rating:&lt;/span>


&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>

&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>

&lt;span class="material-icons">star&lt;/span>
 -->
&lt;p>I am IN LOVE with this dress. It features a flattering empire waistline with a beautiful twist on the front as well as a full circle skirt. The pattern also comes with a choice of sleeves to choose from: three-quarter length, elbow-length, flared or even ruched.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I opted for the flared sleeves, although I didn&amp;rsquo;t make them as flared as suggested in the book. The book tells you how to create the pattern for the flared sleeves and in step 2 tells you to spread the pieces 10cm (4in) apart. I opted for 8cm instead and I love the amount of flare my sleeves have.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tilly and the Buttons: Safiya Trousers</title><link>/blog/safiya-trousers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/safiya-trousers/</guid><description>&lt;p>This pattern is included in the &lt;em>Make it Simple&lt;/em> &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a> book that I got for my birthday recently! I&amp;rsquo;ve never made a pair of trousers before (unless you count PJs) and due to the temperature getting warmer and the sun coming out I thought I should make some nice lightweight summer trousers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fabric used is a linen-cotton mix from &lt;a href="https://poundfabrics.co.uk/">Pound Fabrics&lt;/a> and it&amp;rsquo;s absolutely perfect for lightweight summer clothes.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tilly and the Buttons: Tabitha T-Shirt</title><link>/blog/tabitha-t-shirt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 May 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/tabitha-t-shirt/</guid><description>&lt;p>I've been wanting to try out a &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/tillybuttons">Tilly and the Buttons&lt;/a> pattern for a while now. I&amp;rsquo;m constantly looking at their Instagram page, and loving how aesthetically pleasing it is! I love how they cater to all skill levels and I refer to their blog and Youtube channel frequently because of how clearly everything is explained.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got the &amp;ldquo;Make it Simple&amp;rdquo; Tilly and the Buttons book for my birthday recently and immediately went through the book sticking post-it flags on the pages of the patterns I wanted to try first. Learning to properly sew with stretch fabrics has been a goal of mine for a while, so when I saw that the book had an easy T-shirt pattern I knew that I had to try it. T-shirts are an absolute wardrobe staple and because I&amp;rsquo;m working from home at the moment due to Covid, they are what I wear almost every day.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: The Great British Sewing Bee Shell Top</title><link>/blog/shell-top/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Apr 2021 11:00:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/shell-top/</guid><description>&lt;p>Shell tops aren't really my style but after watching the first episode of The Great British Sewing Bee, series 7, I felt inspired to make one myself. I was mainly intrigued by the &amp;ldquo;bagging out&amp;rdquo; technique for the facing which I had never tried and wanted to learn.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pattern I used is free to download as a PDF and is a very similar shell top to the one used in the episode. It can be found on Sew Mag&amp;rsquo;s website &lt;a href="https://www.sewmag.co.uk/free-sewing-patterns/sewing-bee-sleevless-shell-top">here&lt;/a>. In fact, I think this pattern is from a previous seris of The Sewing Bee!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Sewing Pattern Review: The Amelia Tea Dress</title><link>/blog/amelia-tea-dress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/amelia-tea-dress/</guid><description>&lt;p>Not only is this 50's inspired vintage tea dress absolutely beautiful but the shirred waist and fluttery sleeves make it super comfortable and perfect for the summer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The fabric used was from the sale at &lt;a href="https://poundfabrics.co.uk/">Pound Fabrics&lt;/a> and is a lightweight polyester. It was easy and enjoyable to sew with (after I realised that some of my pins were ruining it so I stopped using them!).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The pattern was easy to follow although I found that there were a few small steps not included such as adding understitching to the neckline facing as well as how to neatly finish seams. I overlocked edges as I went and gave a rolled hem to the skirt for a nice finish.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Free Embroidery Pattern: Flowery Skull</title><link>/blog/skull-pattern/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 11:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/skull-pattern/</guid><description>&lt;p>I absolutely love gothic-esque embroidery and I was inspired by the beautiful Mexican Day of the Dead sugar skulls to create this flowery skull pattern. I have stitched it in a 5&amp;quot; hoop on calico fabric but I also think it would look great on a tote bag, on a denim jacket, or as a patch.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can download the pattern below. To fit the pattern in a 5&amp;quot; hoop make sure your printer does not scale the page, but feel free to scale if you would like the pattern to be smaller or larger.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>