<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Portfolios on JoannaFlorenceMakes</title><link>/portfolio/</link><description>Recent content in Portfolios on JoannaFlorenceMakes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-gb</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 10:42:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Joni Dress</title><link>/portfolio/joni-dress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/joni-dress/</guid><description>The Joni pattern is by Tilly and the Buttons and features in the book Stretch!.
I am IN LOVE with this dress. It features a flattering empire waistline with a beautiful twist on the front as well as a full circle skirt. I opted for the flared sleeve variation.</description></item><item><title>Self Drafted Shirred Top</title><link>/portfolio/shirred-top/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/shirred-top/</guid><description>This pattern was entirely self drafted - yay!
The bodice was so simple to make and started as just two rectangles! The shirring took a long time but it creates a great fit and is so easy to wear.
My overlocker was in for repair when I made this so it was a great chance to practice my French seams!</description></item><item><title>Brighter Days Ahead Rainbow</title><link>/portfolio/brighter-days/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/brighter-days/</guid><description>This beautiful design is by Niamh Wimperis. I saw it on the cover of Mollie Makes magazine and knew I had to stitch it. I gifted it to my auntie for her birthday</description></item><item><title>Safiya Trousers</title><link>/portfolio/safiya-trousers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/safiya-trousers/</guid><description>These are the Safiya Trousers from the Tilly and the Button&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;Make it Simple&amp;rdquo;. They are super comfy. As the book says, it&amp;rsquo;s almost like I&amp;rsquo;m secretly wearing pyjamas!
With this pattern I also succeeded at pattern matching for the first time - yay!</description></item><item><title>The Amelia Tea Dress</title><link>/portfolio/amelia-dress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/amelia-dress/</guid><description>I absolutely LOVE this pattern. It&amp;rsquo;s The Amelia Tea Dress by Simple Sew&amp;hellip; with a few hacks. Firstly, I added some big pockets and attached them in-seam at both the side seams and waist. Secondly, as I didn&amp;rsquo;t have enough fabric for the original pattern I shortened the skirt pattern piece so I was still able to cut out a full circle skirt.
Techniques I learnt in the process were:</description></item><item><title>Strawberry Pinafore Dress</title><link>/portfolio/strawberry-dress/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 10:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/strawberry-dress/</guid><description>When I saw this strawberry covered fabric I immediately thought about making a summery pinafore dress. Then when I saw this pattern for a pinafore dress with large pockets and a pocket on the front I knew I had to make it!
The pattern used was Kwik Sew K4318.
Techniques I learnt in the process were:
Sewing a lapped zip. Turning corners neatly on an overlocker. Stitch in the ditch.</description></item><item><title>I love my dachshund!</title><link>/portfolio/sausage-dog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/sausage-dog/</guid><description>My friend was getting rid of a load of old bed sheets and in them was this gorgeous duvet cover printed with dachshunds, spots, bones and paw prints.
I love recycling fabric and it was great to use this black and tan dachshund as a focal point for a decorative hoop.
I&amp;rsquo;ve still got loads of the fabric left so it&amp;rsquo;ll definitely feature again in the future!
Stitches used: Chain stitch, stem stitch, back stitch.</description></item><item><title>Monochrome Blue</title><link>/portfolio/monochrome-girl/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/monochrome-girl/</guid><description>In 2021 I&amp;rsquo;ve been particpating in the monthly @stitchthisinyourstyle challenge. I love this challenge because it really gets my creative juices flowing every month with a &amp;ldquo;prompt&amp;rdquo; to work into a design.
March&amp;rsquo;s prompt was &amp;ldquo;monochrome&amp;rdquo; so I stitched this &amp;ldquo;blue&amp;rdquo; girl using several different shades of blue.</description></item><item><title>Floral Asymmetrical Dress</title><link>/portfolio/floral-dress/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/floral-dress/</guid><description>This is actually the first dress I&amp;rsquo;ve successfully completed without giving up halfway through! I&amp;rsquo;ve had some sort of mental block about dresses until now. I’ve made plenty of tops and skirts but a dress just seemed like an entirely more difficult thing.
The pattern used was New Look 6507 (view C&amp;hellip; with the adition of a strap).
Techniques I learnt in the process were:
French seams. Making bias binding.</description></item><item><title>Galápagos penguin</title><link>/portfolio/galapagos-penguin/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/galapagos-penguin/</guid><description>One of the reasons I got into embroidery in the first place was because I saw thread-painted animals on Instagram and thought that they looked absolutely beautiful.
For a long while I put off this project because I was scared of doing an injustice to my favourite animal, the penguin. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier with how this turned out though!
This is a Galápagos penguin that I stitched as part of the February 2021 Endangered Species Challenge by @rabbithatdesigns.</description></item><item><title>A Sleepy Sloth</title><link>/portfolio/sloth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/sloth/</guid><description>I recently subscribed to Love Embroidery magazine and this beautiful pattern came in issue 10 (January 2021). It&amp;rsquo;s by Celeste Johnston of @lemon_made_shop and is printed in her book Freshly Stitched.</description></item><item><title>Spill the tea!</title><link>/portfolio/spill-the-tea/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/spill-the-tea/</guid><description>In 2021 I&amp;rsquo;ve been particpating in the monthly @stitchthisinyourstyle challenge. I love this challenge because it really gets my creative juices flowing every month with a &amp;ldquo;prompt&amp;rdquo; to work into a design.
Febuary&amp;rsquo;s prompt was &amp;ldquo;drink&amp;rdquo;. Because I’m British I obviously had to do something involving #tea.</description></item><item><title>My 2020 Mantra</title><link>/portfolio/things-wont/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/things-wont/</guid><description>2020 was a hard year for everyone and this phrase is what I&amp;rsquo;ve been telling myself throughout the entire pandemic.
Something I loved about doing this piece was the lettering. It took hours but it was so theraputic and totally worth it.</description></item><item><title>Green Day Album Art</title><link>/portfolio/american-idiot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/american-idiot/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve always been enamoured with this album artwork and I saw it as a good design to practice my satin stitch.
I restarted this piece three times. Originally I drew the design onto some black fabric but found it difficult to see the design accurately and so switched to calico and coloured the black background with a Sharpie. I kind of love the rusticity of it and I definitely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have got that with a plain black fabric.</description></item><item><title>Nope</title><link>/portfolio/nope/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/nope/</guid><description>In 2021 I&amp;rsquo;ve been particpating in the monthly @stitchthisinyourstyle challenge. I love this challenge because it really gets my creative juices flowing every month with a &amp;ldquo;prompt&amp;rdquo; to work into a design.
January&amp;rsquo;s prompt was &amp;ldquo;one word&amp;rdquo;. &amp;ldquo;Nope&amp;rdquo; pretty much sums up my January.</description></item><item><title>Dave the Dachshund</title><link>/portfolio/dave-the-dachshund/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 13:42:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>/portfolio/dave-the-dachshund/</guid><description>I originally found this free pattern for &amp;ldquo;Dave the Dachshund&amp;rdquo; online from Sew Magazine after wanting to make a doorstop as a present for my sister&amp;rsquo;s birthday (it&amp;rsquo;s not just me that&amp;rsquo;s obsessed with dachshunds!).
After that make, I decided I wanted to make Dave again, but with this super cute avocado fabric! I&amp;rsquo;d never made a soft toy before and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be more pleased with how he turned out.</description></item></channel></rss>